this video is sponsored by headon one of
the best open source platform for
logging monitoring and debugging your
large L model applications so large L
model at default don't have real time
data about what's going on in the world
also don't have access to a company
private data but for majority of use
case you kind of want to bring those
external resource to L model and let it
work Beyond just training data and
traditionally the most popular method
has been rack which represent for
retrieval augmented generation that
basically means you create a big
knowledge base that contain every sing
you want the L language model to know
and when there's a user question or user
query we're do a search in your database
to retrieve the most relevant
information which is a portion of the
whole database and then send both those
retrieve data as well as user question
into the context window of lar L model
but recently this is one term that
became increasingly popular called cak
and cak represent for cage augmented
generation this represent for an
alternative approach instead of doing a
search and put only portion of the rant
data as contacts the key difference of C
is that it pre-load the whole database
into model's contact window all of it
this method has totally changed how do I
build agents and large Lang model
applications that's why today I want to
take you through what exactly does this
method mean when to use rack and c and
most importantly let's try to build an
mCP that using this cak method to pass
any external docs and retrieve the most
random code example from the whole DOC
website without further Ado let's
firstly dive a bit deeper into C this
approach of preload all the data into
contact window do really makes sense 24
months ago cuz back then state of art
large L model contact window is only
4,000 token so you can't really feed
anything more than a small PDF but this
number has dramatically increased for
the past 24 months for now most of the
flagship model support around 100 to
200,000 tokens contact window and
Google's Gemini model it support even up
to 2 million tokens that is 488 times
more than what we have 24 months ago
it's roughly translated to around 1.5
million words and put this into context
for a normal novel it has about 990,000
words and even Book Like War in peace
they only have 587,589
which one so for all the rack pipeline
it start with a data preparation process
like this to turn your data into a
vector database that contains small
chunks of data and then when there's a
new user question we'll also turn users
questions into embedding so that we can
use this embedding to search inside the
vector database and return list of
chunks that is most relevant to what the
user is asking and this is typically
what we call topk results and we
understand both those chunks as well as
user question to the large langage model
prompt and get it to generate accurate
answer but there are few challenges
about building such rack system on one
hand it is a bit complex to setup it
does require some setup to turn your
knowledge into a vector database in this
pipeline it also introduced quite a bit
of latencies for example there will be
time span on actually turning user
crashing into embedding and retrieve the
most revant chunks from the vector
database if your use case is user can
upload a few PDF and start chatting with
PDF it will need to wait for turning all
the PDF docs into a vector database but
most challenging problem is that
retrieval accuracy how can you making
sure the chunks you return here contain
all the information the large L model
will need to answer the user's question
for example for the first step of
splitting your large dock into small
chunks if you just do a very basic and
simple implementation of each chunk is
like 500 characters you might have
situation like this API DOC website but
the actual complete code example will be
breaking down into different chunks so
when large L model receive just one part
of chunks it won't have the full picture
of what the code example actually is on
the other side if your knowledge base
contain financial report across
different years and user just ask a
question what's the latest Revenue it
might return information of revenue from
past years as well which can also
confuse the larange model and sometimes
users question can also be quite complex
if you just simply turn the question
into embedding it might not return all
the information that needed so there's a
whole bunch of techniques that people
are using to resolve those problems like
metadata filtering query transformation
to break down the question into multiple
different small queries reranking and
bunch of other things but K on the other
side because we're fitting the whole
documents into the larg Lang model we
don't need to worry about whether we
retrieve the right information to feed
the large Range model because it must be
somewhere and because we don't need to
do all those vectorizing retrieval
implementation the code implementation
is going to be extremely simple here's a
quick example of how can we build Chad
with PDF use case with a Gemini model
all you need just this 10 lines of code
passing on the doc URL as well as a user
message and will just work out of box
but you might have concern about if we
feed a big document to the large L model
will you be able to retrieve information
accurately as we want and how about the
cost and speed since every time we're
feing such a big prompt to the model
well those three aspects are exactly
three parts that has changed
dramatically for the past few months
especially with Google's Gemini model so
for the first one the retrieval accuracy
typically we're test about something
called the needle in the haast stack
which basically means you are feeding a
huge amount of tax to large L model and
ask to retrieve certain information that
exists in specific parts of this tax and
see if it retrieves things properly on
This research from Google even with
Gemini 1.5 Pro it already demonstrate
near perfect recall of specific
information in vast context of up to 1
million token and with the recently
release of Gemini 2.0 according to this
test from vecta they comparing
hallucination rate of top large L models
Google Gemini 2.0 is achieving an
extraordinary result and we can expect
this number to keep getting better at
with the new models came out on the out
side how about the cost and speed these
two things also changed dramatically
thanks to Gemini so even though some
model like GB 40 the cost can be a bit
higher with $2.5 per million input token
but with model like Gemini 2.0 Flash the
input price for milon token is only 10
cents which is almost 96% cheaper and
with this price point you can really
feed a whole bunch of data to the model
context window without worrying about
the build you will get and meanwhile the
speed also improved a lot in some of
test I did and log on headon I can feed
the whole developer docks from fire CW
to gini 2.0 and for that amount of
contact window the cost is only
0.006 and get results within 3.4 seconds
which is very impressive and if you
haven't heard about headon before headon
is one of the best open source platform
for logging monitoring and debugging lar
L mode application in Productions it
give us ability to see exactly how
people are interacting with our lar
Range model applications track cost
arrow and latencies so we can optimize
for performance and I can also do a
bunch of very Advanced interesting
things like Auto catching the response
if the promp is same to save cost and
improve speed set up customer properties
so I can segment different type of
request and the best part is that it is
extremely easy to set up all you need to
do just adding this part of HTTP options
to your existing gem call then all the
requests will automatically be logged on
the platform I can see exactly what type
of request and prompt user are actually
giving our applications track which part
is creating most of the latency so if
you're building and launching your large
L model applications I highly recommend
you set a headon to capture all the user
request so that you can optimize for the
cost speed and Improvement and now let's
get back to building your C pipeline so
in general my current go-to approach is
I would try to avoid rack and just feed
all context to the large Lage model and
see what kind of results do I get and
based on that I can start doing some
optimizations bra as a message do make
sense and we can often use that to
handle really big data set because even
though the models context window keep
getting bigger and bigger so as company
data is also ever growing so if your use
case require dealing with database that
is really diverse really really big then
rag is still pretty good approach even
though there also approach you can take
with KAG as well assuming your database
very very big that can be feed into just
one large L model context window what
you can do is that you can just use
traditional search to search for which
data are most likely contain the
information that is related to the query
based on either metadata file name and
other stuff and only feed those future
data to large langage model or you can
even do something more fancier for those
data you can do parallel large Range
model call and in the end have another
larg Range model call to summarize the
result to get the best information out
of all those data points so what I want
to do is I will take you through a quick
example of how do we apply those C mes
to some of the really big database use
case and the example I want to show you
is how can you build mCP to enable
cursor or Wing surf to deal with
external docks much better where this
mCP can receive the doc URL and return
only the most relevant code example
based on the stock so first I will
install all the packages that we need
import all of them and also set up
environment keys so we'll be using gini
2.0 flash model so I get API key from
Google AI studio and we'll also use
filec as a service to script in the API
docks as well as headon to log and track
the latency and cost of every single
large range motoc call before we dive
into that I want to give you a quick
example of how can you build this basic
chadow is PDF use case with Gemini 2.0
as I mentioned before it is extremely
extremely simple all we need to do just
created a client of Gemini model and
here I swapped HTTP options to headon
URL so that all those lar Range model
call will be automatically logged there
and then I would download This research
paper here feed both this PDF file as
well as a prompt here to the model and
you can see here it returned the results
which looks correct based on what we see
on the paper here and if we go to headon
you can see that this request that we
just sent cost only
0.00001 and we got a result within three
seconds which quite impressive next
we're going to start building this
external doc mCP pipeline the first
thing I would do is I want to give a
quick test so I will call Gemini
directly with this prompt help me gener
request to script this website using
file if I run this one you can see the
API and point a return here is incorrect
and that's because Gemini didn't really
have the context and knowledge about the
latest documentations of f so this a
great example we can use to test I'll
quickly build a proof concept here
firstly I will use file CS map URL and
point which will return all the sub
Pages under a certain domain and if I
check the lens it return 153 pag in
total so of course we can try to script
all the pages here and send to large
Lang model as context but it will create
quite a bit of latency not just from the
model generation but also scraping takes
quite a long time so what I plan to do
is that I will use Gemini to filter out
only URL that is relevant to the API
reference so I only need to script
relevant page and from this point you
can see a future down to only 27 pag
that is relevant still substantial
amount of context but much smaller than
153 then I can pass on all this 27 links
to the filec batch script URL endpoint
and download the markdown of every
single page so this process does take a
while but what we will do eventually is
save the stocks locally so next time we
don't do script again it will be much
faster cool so you can see that we get
all the markdown content for all the
pages which is quite a big context I'm
going to feed all the markdowns above
along with the same that we sent to Gim
before and let it generate result so
with this one you can see get result
poply it pick up the right end point as
well as a request body format and if I
go to headon you can see for this
request where we download the whole API
DOC website across 27 page it cost
around
0.006 and get a result within 2 seconds
which is really really fast so this is
how simple and easy it is now to give
large L models knowledge and Gemini also
have this contestation feature which
means for those those large contexts we
can actually create a cage then the next
time when user try to create the same
doc we can just pass that cage to the
model class so it will be even faster in
terms of generation but unfortunately at
moment this contestation functionality
does support Gemini 2.0 model so I will
leave this part later when it is
available and I also turn this pipeline
into an mCP server where it has this
function called retrieve API doc users
can just give the request and share the
doc URL and this mCP will handle all the
work in terms of retrieving the most
rant code example from the doc itself so
my cursor and Wing server can work with
external docs much better and there are
also optimizations I did where it will
automatically save all the script
markdown file locally so we don't need
to script again again if you're
interested in using this mCP I have put
mCP server repo in the AI Builder Cloud
community and building with a
step-by-step process of how to set up as
well as the notebook example that I took
you through in the video today so if
you're interested you can click on the
link below to join the community or
continuously posting interest learnings
and tips about building production ready
large L model application as well as
advanced AI coding tips but more
importantly you have this community of
top AI Builders who are launching their
own AI set so you can come and ask any
question you have both me and other
Community member can just come and share
any insights we have I hope you enjoy
this video thank you and I see you next
time